ADITYA KUMAR () Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, JavaScript, ADO. Net, iQuery, AJAX, JSON, CSS, TFS, Git



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: NIIT Technologies Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Delhi Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Gurgaon, Pune, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer/Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Project

Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Application

Support, JavaScript, ADO. Net, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, CSS, TFS, Git

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Professional with approx 5 years of experience in Implementation, Delivery and Deployment of applications.

Currently Working as Senior Software Engineer at NIIT Technologies from May 2019 to till now.

Earlier associated as Software Engineer at Chetu India Pvt Ltd from Dec 2017 to May 2019.

Earlier associated as Software Developer at Para Solutions Pvt Ltd from Dec 2015 to Dec 2017.

Good understanding of C#, ASP.NET, Asp.Net Core, OOPS, REST API, T-SQL, MVC, JavaScript, Typescript, Angular 8.

Possess good working knowledge in working with TFS and GIT.

Involved in end-to-end development life cycle including design, estimation, development, unit-testing and releases.

Excellent code writing, reviews and debugging skills.

Correct errors by making appropriate changes and then rechecking the program to ensure that the desired results are produced. Strong experience in completing task on time following best coding practices and guidelines.

Work Experience

NIIT Technologies as Senior Software Engineer

May 2019 to Till Date

May 2019 to present

Application Maintenance and

Development Developer

Visual studio(2017) C#, Asp.net MVC, Core

API, ling, Jquery, JavaScript, Sql Server 2017,

CMS(Tridion) and Angular 8 Synopsis

This is web based project. Holidays(https://holidays.flydubai.com) is Tour Package booking website by flydubai, Mainly deals in package booking including Hotel + Flight with both b2c and b2b business

model. Created new API and worked on DealsBanner and Destination card module, sitemap, performance improvement of website enhancement module.

Chetu India Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer

Dec 2017 to May 2019

Name of the Project- LoanBeam SharperLending API (https://loanbeam.com) Duration Project Type Role

Technology July 2018 to May 2019

New Development Developer

Visual Studio 17/19, C#, Asp.net core 2.1, RabbitMQ, Hangfire, Sql Server 2017, JMeter, groovy Synopsis

This is the Web API based project. The client of these projects contest finance domain of the loan company. It provides the loan to the customer and based on this API verified the customer documentation. Here the loanbeam has multiple client that access API to verify the customer document and loan beam API send the document in base 64 encoded format to sharper lending lender where sharper lending confirm documents from different departments and send back to the response after certain time period using RabbitMQ.

Duration

Project Type Role

Technology Dec 2017 to June 2018

Application Maintenance and Development Developer

Visual studio 15/17, C#, MVC, Ling,

Jquery, JavaScript, WebAPI,

Sql Server 2014 Synopsis

This is the exiting web project. The client of these projects contest finance domain of the loan

company. ?t provided the loan to customer and based on this all client information regarding the loan process and status it's maintaining the all information on Dash broad and all information is visible in

Kendo UI. We have managed the view structure and manage the server side functionality

Para Solutions Pvt Ltd as Software Developer

Dec 2015 to Dec 2017

Duration

Project Type Role

Technology May 2014 to August 2015

Application Maintenance and Enhancement Developer

Visual studio(2013) C# .Net, Asp.net

Webform, Ado.Net, Jquery, JavaScript,

Sql Server 2012, Service Desk Synopsis

TRW Automotive(trw.com) is Auto Company, which manufactures and innovates new technology for vehicles. Specializing in engineering, it is primarily known for its design, research and development, and manufacturing activities in the automotive industry. It is a worldwide supplier of driveline and chassis technology for cars and commercial vehicles, along with specialist plant equipment such as construction equipment. http://vin.ssc.trw.com is supplier portal that is designed to facilitate seamless communication between TRW internal users and suppliers.

Education

UG: B.Com (Commerce) from University of Delhi in 2011

PG: MCA (Computers) from Sikkim Manipal University (SMU) in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Java Script, CSS, AJAX, JSON, jQuery			
MVC, Asp.Net Core, WEB API, MVC, MVVM			
Angular 8, RabbitMQ, TypeScript			
SQL Server, Visual Studio, Agile			
TFS, GIT, VS Code, MS VSTS			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

Hindi

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time